Thomas Maestas

Software Developer

Albuquerque, NM 87104 thomas.maestas@hotmail.com +1.505.508.7707

I specialize in latest app software technologies, with a Masters-level understanding of data analytics and visualization. I have 7 years of experience with web app UI, including AngularJS and React; Granular knowledge of HTML5-CSS3-ES6 JavaScript syntax; task-runners including Gulp, Grunt, Webpack; and cloud proficiency including AWS, GCP, and Firebase. My data-focused experience includes MongoDB-Express-Angular-Node.js and Django-Python, and relational proficiency including MySQL and PostgreSQL. Full Life-cycle dev experience, using Agile Methodology.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

App Software Consultant

THM Software Solutions (Contract title: Software Consultant) - Albuquerque, NM April 2019 to Present

Trouble-Shooting and testing program applications using Angular and AngularJS UI frameworks. JavaScript refactoring and syntax migration to ES6.

Associate Software Developer (Contracting as Software Engineer)

Rural Sourcing Inc - Albuquerque, NM May 2018 to April 2019

RSI client role was Software Engineer, using Scrum/Agile methodology using Confluent Jira storyboard within a seven-person UX/Dev team for the GUI of a data funnel, team members daily Skyping from New York, U.K. and France. Within team, responsible for API and UI logic for a REST API database-related software application.

Software Developer

Xpansiv Data - Albuquerque, NM July 2017 to January 2018

While contracting for Xpansiv, I led exploratory research into Python-based data visualization tools, in order to contrast with the in-use JavaScript-based libraries like D3js and Raw. Along with specializing in data-related visualization, Our team of two developed an application using Node and React-based Proof-Concept using D3js charting.

Social Statistics Teaching Assistant

Université de Montréal - Montreal, Canada August 2016 to December 2016

In Fall 2016, I began doctoral studies at the University of Montreal, Dept. of Sociology, studying quantitative analysis, including regression and factorial analysis. I worked as a Teaching Assistant for 2 100-level courses, 101 and Research Methods, with lab and office hour duties.

Webmaster (Contracted as Graduate Assistant)

Department of Sociology, University of New Mexico - Albuquerque, NM September 2013 to December 2015

Webmaster, creating and/or maintaining sections in Sociology Department Website, using XSLT, JavaScript, and custom CSS. Secondly, I installed and maintained graduate computer lab software, including maintenance of lab machines generally.

Conference Presenter

National Institutes of Health (NIH) - Bethesda, MD June 2015 to June 2015

June 26-27, 2015. Presented Statistical Analysis Paper at NIH Adolescent Health Analytics Conference. "Great Expectations: A Study on the Determinants of Adolescent College Graduation Expectations"

Research Assistant

Statistical Analysis Center at UNM Institute of Statistical Research (ISR) - Albuquerque, NM September 2013 to March 2014

Duties included database queries and analylsis of education- and criminology-related data collections and analysis, co-authoring and editing of institute-published reports.

Principle Investigator

Ethnographic Mixed-Method Research Project 2013 to 2014

IRB

#13-223, "The Role of Academic Cultural Capital on the Transfer Aims of Two-Year Collegiates"

Education

M.A. in Sociology

University of New Mexico - Albuquerque, NM December 2015

B.A. in History

University of New Mexico - Albuquerque, NM December 2001

Skills

MySQL (1 year), PHP (Less than 1 year), Javascript (7 years), Python (2 years), AngularJS (1 year), React (1 year), Unit and End-to-End Testing (Karma/Jasmine/Protractor) (1 year), Linux, OS X, MS-DOS (Command-line proficiency) (10+ years), jQuery, HTML 5, Git, CSS

Links

https://ourdailytech.net

Groups

ABQ Python

August 2018 to Present

Monthly Python Meetup, including live-coding presentations and discussion on theme.

Albuquerque AWS Meetup

November 2018 to Present

Monthly meetings focus on different AWS services. Live-coding applications covering meeting topic; Topics include Rekognition, Lambda functions, API Gateway with S3, etc.

505 React

September 2018 to Present

At Monthly meetings, make a new themed JavaScript components and React applications, along with lecture from host or guest. Examples include a chatting app, calculator app using Redux.

Additional Information

Fluent in French, Proficient in Spanish;